

832-659-7048

chrischan8551@gmail.com

Portfolio

LinkedIn

Githul

SKILLS JavaScript, Java, Express.js, Node.js, Python, React, Redux, Sequelize, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, RESTful API

### **PROJECTS**

Pholickr | (React / Redux, Python, HTML, CSS)

live | github

- Final capstone is a fully interactive app inspired by Flickr with the implementation of four full CRUD functionalities. I
  encountered the challenge of working with a large seed base in the database which prompted the need to refactor
  my code to improve query performance and time complexity. This experience reminded me of the importance of
  continuously testing and evaluating code for optimal performance.
- Refactored all necessary code to improve query performance and time complexity.
- Deployed via Render, and incessantly tested the app's functionalities for optimal performance.

Pinteresting | (React / Redux, Python, HTML, CSS)

live | github

- Assimilated a team of 5 as the technical project lead to ensure that the team was working towards a common goal by streamlining the process, effective communication, ensure a streamlined process and successful project delivery
- Produced a strategy for recreating Pinterest's linked feature. The new feature should be designed in a way that simplifies the linking process and improving its intuitiveness to enhance user experience.

Sound Puff | (Express / Javascript, HTML, CSS, AWS)

<u>live</u>l <u>github</u>.

- Constructed a simple music streaming application integrated with AWS similar to SoundCloud, focusing on delivering a minimalist design using CSS, and a seamless user experience
- Crafted a detailed scope of work for the first iteration of the Sound Puff user interface, implementing two full CRUDs by the sprint's completion.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Warehouse Manager and Operations Administrator

June 2015 - Present

DHL, a global logistics organization that acquired Hillebrand in 2022. Prior to the acquisition, Hillebrand had acquired Braid in 2021, resulting in the integration of industry-leading logistics companies with a bulk liquids division.

- Operations Oversaw a portfolio of 20+ clients, ensuring seamless operations process by coordinating with steamship lines, trucking companies, flexitank installers, and scheduling with loading plants. Demonstrated ocean logistics expertise in preparing and submitting critical shipment documents, including customs clearance documents, to ensure compliance with relevant regulations. Consistently delivered high levels of customer satisfaction by treating them as priority.
- Inventory Management Effectively managed the procurement and distribution of more than 10,000 flexitanks and
  their components across the United States and Canada. Proactively utilized cost optimization strategies to identify
  and engage with vendors offering the lowest possible transit costs, resulting in 10-20% cost savings. I ensured
  optimal inventory levels, minimized stockouts, and reduced excess inventory through strong vendor management,
  negotiations, and exceptional communication skills, resulting in successful outcomes.
- Incident Management Responsible for mitigating incidents at ports, trucking depots, and plant sites. Prepare and submit detailed incident reports to customers, including root cause analysis. Successfully implemented cost-saving measures by managing incidents in-house, resulting in substantial cost reductions compared to outsourcing to external companies.

#### **Procurement Specialist**

Axistrade June 2014 - June 2015

• Efficiently sourced all requested items from leading S&P 500 oil and gas companies, while prioritizing cost optimization to maximize profit margins. Proactively sought out cost-effective solutions to minimize expenses while maintaining high levels of guality and timely delivery.

# **EDUCATION**

AppAcademy - 1000-hour immersive full-stack web development intensive with < 3% acceptance rate, 2023 University of Texas at San Antonio - BS Business Administration and Management, 2001-2005